Thomas F. Walsh Papers
Thomas F. Walsh Papers
1901-1919
Walsh, Thomas F. (Thomas Francis), 1850-1910.
0.5 linear feet
American miner and mining engineer. Collection contains correspondence, chiefly social; autographs; bankbooks; funeral cards; photos; telegrams; and a published address by Walsh.
148734
Biographical History
Thomas F. Walsh (1850-1910) was an Irish-American miner and philanthropist. After working as a millwright and carpenter in Ireland, he came to the United States and began mining for gold in the Black Hills and Colorado. His eventual discovery of the rich Camp Bird Mine yielded more than $20 million in gold and other minerals. A friend of Presidents McKinley, Roosevelt, and Taft, Walsh also endowed two libraries as well as a research fund at the Colorado School of Mines for the study of radium and other minerals, and contributed to many other social causes both in Ireland and the United States.
A biography of Walsh, Thomas F. Walsh: Progressive Businessman and Colorado Mining Tycoon by John C Stewart, was published in 2007.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Thomas F. Walsh Papers consists of correspondence, primarily incoming, a few subject files, and one published item.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by sender. Subject files are arranged alphabetically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Business and Industry; Science and medicine; Walsh, Thomas F. (Thomas Francis), 1850-1910.; Gold miners -- Colorado.; Gold mines and mining -- Colorado.; Correspondence.; Photographs.; Miners.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Thomas F. Walsh, 1963.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Balinger, R. A., 1908 (Box 1)
  - Bartel, G. C., 1909 (Box 1)
  - Bennett, Charles G., 1918 (Box 1)
  - Blythswood, Renfrew, 1908 (Box 1)
  - Brind, Miran, undated (Box 1)
  - Buchtel, Henry, 1907 (Box 1)
  - Burrows, J. C., 1909 (Box 1)
  - Butler, Michael, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Carpenter, Fred W., 1909 (Box 1)
  - Cortelyou, George B., 1909 (Box 1)
  - Corcoran, Thom, 1908 (Box 1)
  - Curtiss, William E., 1902 (Box 1)
  - Dewey, George, 1909 (Box 1)
  - Executive Chamber of Colorado, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Fairbanks, Chester, 1908 (Box 1)
  - Governor of Ohio, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Grant, Frederick, 1909 (Box 1)
  - Hay, Clara S., 1903 (Box 1)
  - Hay, John, 1902 (Box 1)
  - Houston, Samuel, 1914 (Box 1)
  - Loeb, William Jr., 1908 (Box 1)
  - Louise, 1910 (Box 1)
  - McCrey, 1908 (Box 1)
  - Maenagh, Franklin, 1909 (Box 1)
  - McLanahan & Burton, 1919 (Box 1)
  - Miller, Anne Jean, 1909 (Box 1)
  - Petherick, 1910 (Box 1)
  - Skinner, James, 1909 (Box 1)
  - Smith, Maggie, 1910 (Box 1)
  - Stockquart, Emile, 1908 (Box 1)
  - Sherman, J. S., 1909 (Box 1)
  - Taft, William Howard, 1908 (Box 1)
  - Vandike, Henry, undated (Box 1)
  - Walsh, Winifred, 1910 (Box 1)
  - Walsh, Blanch, 1901 (Box 1)
  - Walsh, Catharine, 1910 (Box 1)
  - Walsh, Sister Mary Borgia, 1909 (Box 1)
  - Waddinfor, Hing, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Wallace, —, undated (Box 1)
  - Warren, 1909 (Box 1)
  - War Department, undated (Box 1)
  - Outgoing correspondence, from Thomas F. Walsh, 1909 (Box 1)
- Subject files
  - Autographs (Box 1)
  - Bank books (Box 1)
  - Club lists (Box 1)
  - Design for stamps (Box 1)
  - Finances (Box 1)
  - Funeral cards (Box 1)
  - Notes (Box 1)
  - Photographs (Box 1)
  - Pass to International Exposition, Paris (Box 1)
  - Speech (Box 1)
  - Telegrams (Box 1)
- Published material
  - Address by Thomas F. Walsh (Box 1)